Ok. What defines you better?
好啊，那你以什麼身份去？
Business Consultant at Mckenzie or Naveen Bansal's girlfirend?
麥肯錫的商業顧問還是納文·班薩爾的女朋友？
Ravi Ram Rastogi.
拉維 · 拉斯托吉
CEO, CTO, CMO
首席執行官、首席技術官、首席營銷官
Founder, Superentreprenuer.com
Superentreprenuer.com 創始人
This is my 8th company
這是我的第八家公司
and about those seven before this?
在這之前的那七家呢？
They were shut down.
都倒閉了
We have to talk to the judges now
我們現在得和評委談談
Is Narayan Murthy here yet?
納拉揚·穆西來了嗎？
So the event staff has seeked a new replacement now
活動工作人員現在已經找到了一個新的替代者
How dare you stop people from entering the competition?
你怎麼能阻止別人參加比賽？
Can you just get the other teams to sign on a paper That they're okay with you participating
你們能不能讓其他團隊簽一份說明讓他們同意你參賽
Don't even think about working in a startup, okay?
不能去創業公司工作，明白嗎？
Do you hear me?
你聽到了嗎？
Actually, he didn't tell you the whole thing
事實上，他冇有跟你說實情
He wants to carry on with the startup
他想繼續創業
Alright then, it seems like my words have no meaning here
好吧，看來我的話在這裏冇有任何意義
You tried your best dear
你已經盡力了，親愛的
i didn't give up and run back
我冇有放棄
but i choose to stand here to face you guys
而是選擇站在這裏
Rajat you told me that I cannot sell my product here on stage
拉傑，你告訴我，我不能在臺上賣我的産品
Therefore I sold myself
所以我賣自己
by the way i'm Puneet i work for a vc firm, and this is my card
順便說一嘴，我是普尼特，這是我的名片
I'm free on thursday afternoon, what are you guys doing on thursday?
我星期四下午有空，你們星期四有時間嗎？
So, Karunesh invited his girlfriend over
所以卡魯內什邀請他的女朋友過來
I told him to use the lower bed frame of the bunk bed and I'll use the upper one
我跟他說你們睡下層，我睡上層
You enjoy your privacy
你倆好好玩
He agreed
他同意了
But Mohanti made an MMS clip of them in the night
但是莫漢蒂晚上錄了他們的小視頻
And forwarded the clip to me
然後把視頻轉發給了我
He became upset in the morning and started yelling at me
他在早上起來非常生氣，開始對我大喊大叫
It wasn't even my fault
這甚至都不是我的錯
Listen Rastogi!
聽著，拉斯托吉！
Have you heard of Ronald Wayne?
你聽說過羅納德 · 韋恩嗎？
Who?
誰？
Ronald Wayne, ever heard of him?
羅納德 · 韋恩，聽說過他嗎？
Was he Batman's father?
他是蝙蝠俠的父親嗎？
He was an entrepreneur
他是一個企業家
40 years ago he started a company with his 2 friends
40年前，他和他的兩個朋友開了一家公司
Today that company is worth billions of dollars
今天，這家公司價值數十億美元
But Nobody knows him
但是冇有人認識他
Do you know what is the name of that company?
你知道那家公司的名字嗎？
What?
什麼名字？
Apple
蘋果
Everyone knows who Steve Jobs was
每個人都知道史蒂夫 · 喬佈斯是誰
Many people might know about Steve Wozniak too
很多人可能也知道史蒂夫 · 沃茲尼亞克
But no one ever remembers the name of the 3rd guy
但是冇有人記得第三個人的名字
And look I'm the 4th guy
而我是第四個人
Yogi said something?
尤吉說了什麼嗎？
Don't be antsy about what Yogi said, He is probably annoyed with his hairfall
不要因為尤吉說的話而不高興，他可能是因為脫發而生氣
What could he even say?
他還能說什麼呢？
I'll whoop his sorry ass someday, He hasn't seen my livid side yet
總有一天我會痛扁他一頓，他還冇看到我粗暴的一麵
But Jeetu?
但是傑圖呢？
I told him on the phone last week that its a bank holiday on the 1st of next month
我上周在電話裏告訴他，下個月一號是銀行休假日
Following with a weekend
接著就是是一個周末
So his salary would be 3,4 days overdue
所以他的薪水可能會晚三四天
He disconnected the phone halfway
他直接就掛電話了
How rude!
真冇禮貌！
Do you know what Naveen said when I told him about this?
你知道我告訴納文這件事時他說了什麼嗎？
I'm busy Mandal I'll talk to you later
我很忙，曼達爾，我晚點再和你談
Go make some tea for me
去給我泡杯茶
Is this a way to talk to a CMO?
這是和首席營銷官講話的方式嗎？
Not at all
根本不是
Sometimes it feels like that I'm nothing, Rastogi
有時候我覺得自己什麼都不是，拉斯托吉
I mean
我是說
Naveen gives presentations
納文做了産品展示
Jeetu does coding
傑圖負責編碼
Yogi gets to meet with vendors
尤吉去拉供應商
No one gives me any work to do
冇人給我安排正經的事情做
I think I'm a zero
我覺得我就和空氣一樣
Don't fret over these stupid little things
不要為這些愚蠢的小事煩惱
Look at me, I've been fighting for 14 years
看看我，我已經奮鬥了14年
Look at you, who is gonna bag seed funding in just 6 months
而你6個月後就能拿到種子資金了
From none other than Plutus atlantic
而且是來自大西洋資本
You're only left with the partner meeting now
現在隻剩下合夥人會議了
Then everyone will acknowledge your reputation in the market
到時候每個人都會承認你在市場上的聲譽
I don't need any respect from the market, Rastogi
我不需要市場的任何尊重，拉斯托吉
I just want my 3 friends to respect me
我隻是想讓我的三個朋友尊重我
Then show them your dedication
那你就要嚮他們展示你的奉獻精神
Give your blood, sweat and tears to this startup
為你們的事業奉獻你的血汗和淚水
Go the extra mile and they'll start respecting you
多做一些事情，他們就會開始尊重你
How else am I going to show them dedication?
我還要怎麼嚮他們展示我的奉獻精神呢？
I am the one who works his ass off for Jeetu 5 days a week
我一周五天為傑圖鞍前馬後
I get exhausted by the evening but I still cook dinner for Yogi and Naveen
到了晚上我已經筋疲力盡了，但我還是會為尤吉和納文做晚飯
I go around all day with this pen drive clinging to me
我整天帶著這個U盤走來走去
If this isn't enough dedication then I don't know what is
如果這樣奉獻的還不夠，那我真不知道該怎麼做了
What's with this pen drive?
這個U盤是怎麼回事？
All the company's secrets
公司所有的秘密
Everything important to the company...
所有重要的文件
...is in this pen drive
都在這個U盤裏麵
This is what will make our company big
這個U盤能使我們的公司成為大公司
I update it after every meeting
每次會議後我都會更新
I was in New York last year, got it from there for $5
我去年在紐約，花了5美元買來的
But I'm sure that this same device will get us 5 Billion dollars one day
但我確信這個5塊錢的U盤有一天會給我們帶來50億美元的收入
Why don't you drink this? huh?
你怎麼不喝這個？
Yeah Chill out!
放輕鬆
No no no no
不不不不
I will drink only beer...
我隻喝啤酒.
I have a digestion problem with these inferior quality drinks
我喝這種劣質飲料會不舒服
Drink up, there's nothing wrong with it
喝吧，這冇什麼不好的
This is Rastogi's special
特別推薦
This is what we were selling in our 6th startup venture
這是我們第六次創業時賣的東西
Colombo Tsunami
科倫坡海嘯
The title is a little insensitive
這個名字起得不好
Otherwise Tiger Global would've been onboard just like that
否則老虎環球公司絕對會給我們投錢
Just for you, I'll have one sip
就沖你這句話，我就喝一小口
Okay, two
好吧，兩口
Jeetu's wife is so hot man
傑圖老婆超性感
Really?
真的嗎？
And so cultured
而且很有教養
I don't know where my mom finds these dumb bimbos and insists me to meet them
我不知道我媽在哪裏找到這些蠢女人，還堅持要我去見她們
I once asked a girl, "What do you like about Avatar?"
我曾經問過一個女孩，“你喜歡《阿凡達》的什麼? ”
She said, "Rajesh Khanna(*Actor in Avtaar) is so cute"
她說: “拉傑什·坎納(Avtaar 演員)太可愛了.”
I mean what the fuck girls?
這都什麼鬼啊？
Sorry, I'll be back in 2 minutes, Nature's call
抱歉，我兩分鍾後回來，憋不住了
Come back in a jiffy
快點回來
You have to pay the bill
你得付賬
Of course, I had a good time
當然，我玩得很開心
Thank you!
謝謝你！
No no, thank you
不，不，謝謝你才對
If they ask you about the salary, tell them to give you a minute to think
如果他們問你期望薪資多少，告訴他們給你點時間考慮一下
Tell the HR that you'll manage your own transportation
告訴hr你自己開車上下班
They'll be as pleased as punch
他們會非常高興的
Guys, Uber is booked Cab will be here in Five
夥計們，優步已經接單了，五分鍾後到
Hurry-up Naveen! We have to double check
快點，納文! 我們要再確認一下
If it weren't for my VP promotion, I wouldn't be fighting for you
如果不是因為要升副總，我才不會來
I'm doing this because your product is promising
我這麼做是因為你們的産品很有前途
Stop yammering, I've been ready since last night
別抱怨了，我從昨晚就準備好了
I even slept wearing the tie
我係著領帶睡覺
Jeetu, come along now
傑圖，過來
Hold on a minute
等一下
Check in the closet drawer, there must be a white carry bag
檢查衣櫃的抽屜，裏麵一定有一個白色的手提包
Yes the one with Kalyani sari
是的，有卡利亞尼紗麗的那個
You'll find your certificate, passport, checkbook and every document in it.
你能找到你的證件、護照、支票簿和其他文件.
What is he up to?
他在幹什麼？
Soumya is interviewing for a job today
她老婆今天要麵試一份工作
He's been blabbering about his postmodern post-marriage love story for 2 hours
他已經絮叨兩個小時了
Hey Yogi!
嘿，尤吉
Have you seen my pen drive?
你看見我的U盤了嗎？
Which one?
哪一個？
The same with...
跟那個一樣的
Yogi has already taken 2 or 3 backups of the presentation
尤吉已經做了兩三個備份了
Oh hello!
餵，聽著
Six backups
六個備份
No its not here
不，不在這裏
Mandal, sit your ass down
曼達爾你給我坐下
Mandal, sit down there
曼達爾，坐下
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Naveen, what the hell is going on?
納文你怎麼回事？
Naveen, come along What are you even doing here?
納文，過來！你在這裏幹什麼？
I could only sleep for 4 hours, At least let me wash my face
我隻能睡4個小時，至少讓我洗洗臉
We're finally getting the funding today
我們今天終於要拿到資金了
My luck is shining and so should my face, No?
我的運氣在閃耀，我的臉也應該閃耀，不是嗎？
You guys are taking this meeting very lightly
你們這些家夥太小看這次會議了
I'm telling you since day 1...
這麼跟你說吧
...everyone in the firm is liking your idea but this has nothing to do with seed funding
就算公司裏的每個人都喜歡你的主意，那也跟你能不能拿到錢冇關係
All that matters is whether Bhardwaj likes it or not
重要的是巴德瓦伊喜不喜歡
We've just 30 minutes left, Come along now come on come on
我們隻剩下30分鍾了，來吧，快過來
You guys are so tardy...
你們就快遲到了
...Turn it off
把它關掉
Alright I'm sitting down
好了，我坐下了
No no get up
不，不，起來
Just be punctual, Temples can wait
一定要準時，寺廟可以晚點去
Jeetu!
傑圖！
Alright I'm hanging up
好吧，我掛了
Hey listen, breakfast is in the fridge Eat properly, Okay?
聽著，早餐在冰箱裏，記得吃，好嗎？
Oh and have some sweet yoghurt, it'll bring you good luck
哦，還有甜酸奶，它會給你帶來好運
All the best
一切順利
Wish her good luck for me
替我祝她好運
Naveen wishes you all the best
納文祝你一切順利
Wish her for me too
也替我祝福她
Just say it simultaneously and be done with it guys
行了，別bb了
No its nothing, Puneet wishes you all the best. I'll talk to you later
不，冇什麼，普尼特祝你一切順利.我晚點再打給你
Sorry
對不起
Do you guys know that Ideally I shouldn't even be here
你們知道嗎? 理想情況下我根本不該來這裏
Why did I come here?
我為什麼來這裏？
The most important...
最重要的是...
With whom are you guys meeting?
你們要和誰見麵？
Ankit Bhardwaj, senior partner Plutus Atlantic
太平洋資本的資深合夥人安吉·巴特瓦吉
Do you guys have any idea who is he?
你們知道他是誰嗎？
He's known as Midas Bhardwaj in the VC circles
在風投圈子裏，他被稱為邁達斯·巴德瓦吉
Is it Midas or Midaas?
是邁迪斯還是邁達斯？
Shut up you benighted fool
你閉嘴
He has 17 multi million dollar companies in his portfolio and zero in his anti portfolio
他的投資組合中有市值1700多萬美元的公司，而他的反投資組合中卻冇有一家
What's anti portfolio?
什麼是反投資組合？
What is investor's portfolio?
什麼是投資者的投資組合？
The companies he chose to fund and they became successful
他選擇投資的公司都很成功
Then what is its ANTI?
那麼它的反義詞是什麼？
The companies he chose not to fund and yet they became successful
那些他選擇不投資的公司，卻取得了成功
Exactly
冇錯
Bhardwaj doesn't have any header of anti-portfolio in his profile
巴德瓦伊在他的個人資料中冇有任何反投資組合的標題
Now if he rejects your idea today...
如果他今天拒絕你的提議...
...then mark my words no one will give a flying fuck to your idea in Bombay or Bangalore
記住我的話，在孟買或班加羅爾，就不會有人看好你們了
Now you don't want to go to Delhi and I don't want to remain as an analyst forever
那麼既然你們不想去德裏，我也不想永遠做一個分析師
So let's focus on it together, Okay?
所以讓我們一起專註這件事，好嗎？
Those 30 minutes inside that room...
在那個房間裏的30分鍾...
...can take your lives in two completely opposite direction
決定你們上天堂還是下地獄
You have an impressive product and you did a lot of elbow grease on it
你有一個令人印象深刻的産品，你做了很多辛苦的工作
This is what it boils down to
就是這樣
And don't forget to lick his balls the minute you enter there
還有進去的時候別忘了先好好舔他
Alright guys, cab is here Let's leave
好了，出租車來了我們走吧
Naveen, button your shirt to the neck
納文，把你的襯衫扣子係好
Mandal- I couldn't find it
曼達爾，我找不到
Puneet- Guys hurry up!
小朋友們，快點！
Jeetu- Let me put on my shoes
傑圖-讓我穿上鞋子
Jeetu- Mandal did you wear my socks again?
傑圖 -曼達爾 你又穿我的襪子了？
Mandal- No, I'm wearing my own
- 曼達爾 - 不，我穿的是自己的
Jeetu, your demo is ready?
傑圖，你的演示版準備好了嗎？
What about FB login?
那麼Facebook登錄呢？
Oh, not yet
哦，還冇有
I'll do it in the cab
我在出租車上做
Yeah okay
好吧
Should I wear a tie?
我應該打領帶嗎？
You can wear boxers in their let alone tie
你穿內褲去都行
Ankit, Naveen and team
安基特，納文和他的團隊
hi, i'm Ankit. -Naveen
你好，我是安基特
you guys want anything？tea？coffee？
你們要喝點什麼嗎？-不用了
Sir, I saw your TED Talk it was very thought provoking
我看了你的演講，非常發人深省
Which one? California or Vancouver?
哪個演講? 加利福尼亞還是溫哥華？
Both of them
兩個都看了
Really? Vancouver is next month
真的嗎? 下個月才去溫哥華
Puneet, you want anything?
普尼特，你要點什麼嗎？
I'm sorry guys but...
很抱歉，但是...
No no its okay feel free
不，不，冇關係，你吃你的
Missed the breakfast, now my wife is making me eat oats as a punishment
早餐冇吃，現在我妻子要我吃燕麥作為懲罰
You guys are married?
你們結婚了嗎？
Only me sir
隻有我結婚了，先生
Oh, so girlfriends?
那你們有女朋友了嗎
Sir, Naveen has one
先生，納文有女朋友
So Ankit, should we start the presentation?
那麼安基特，我們要現在開始演示嗎？
Naveen
納文
Uh no wait a second
不，等一下
Hold on for a minute
等一下
Guys...
夥計們...
...on my way back from bangalore today
今天我從班加羅爾回來的路上……
And I must say the idea has lot of potential
我必須說這個想法有很大的潛力
The targets that you guys have mentioned are quite realistic and achievable
你們提到的目標是相當現實並且是實現的
And the revenue model is also very impressive
而且收入模式也令人印象深刻
Thank you sir
謝謝，先生
BUT...
但是...
And I say the BUT in capital letters
我要強調但是
Couple of days back, few guys presented me...
就在幾天前，有幾個人給我介紹了...
...the exact same idea with the exact same targets
想法和目標與你們完全一緻
and the exact same revenue models
並且收入模式也完全一緻
Now I'm not sure how this has happened
我不知道這是怎麼回事
Hold on a minute, Ankit
等一下，安吉特
I've been with these guys for last 3,4 weeks now I'm pretty convinced that its their original idea...
我和這些人在一起已經三四個星期了，我非常確信這個想法是他們原創的
I don't think they have stolen it or..
我不認為他們會剽竊或者...
No no I'm not accusing anybody
不，不，我冇有指責任何人
Even for me this is a unique situation
即使對我來說，這也是一個特殊的情況
But two teams with exactly the same idea..
但是兩個團隊有著完全相同的想法.
can't just be a coincidence
不可能隻是巧合
But we have this idea since college...
但是我們從大學起就有這個想法...
sorry,sorry
抱歉
But Ankit we've been on this since college
但是安吉特，我們從大學就開始研究這個了
If you want I can also show you our chat and conversation over mail
如果你想看的話，我也可以把我們內部的溝通郵件給你看
We've been planning this for 3 years
我們已經計畫了3年
Guys guys I'm not a detective
老弟，我不是偵探
I'm an investor
我是一個投資者
And the same product has been pitched to me twice by 2 different teams
同樣的産品被兩個不同的團隊兩次推薦給我
Sir, I mean can you disclose their names?
先生，你能透露他們的名字嗎？
Well...
好吧.
I can't reveal their names at this point of time
現在我不能透露他們的名字
And...
還有...
This changes few things for you guys
這對你們來說就有了一些改變
Let me explain you how the investment process really works
讓我來解釋一下投資到底是如何運作的
So, in this sea of unknown
在這片未知的海洋裏
You guys are sitting here on this island
你們在這個島上
Comfortably with your idea
帶著你們滿意的創業想法
Let's call this island..
我們把這個島叫做.
Comfort zone
舒適區
And I'm here on this island
我在這個島上
Where magic happens
神奇的事情發生了
This is where big companies are formed
這就是大公司形成的地方
Now you guys have to reach here
現在你們必須到這裏來
There are 2 options
有兩種選擇
One..
一.
You step out of your comfort zone and start swimming
你走出你的舒適區，開始遊泳
You'll have to face the waves of uncertainty, the tides of sacrifice
你將不得不麵對不確定的浪潮
The unpredictable climate change of destiny
命運無法預測的氣候變化
And... I'm not sure if you're gonna make it to there
還有... 我不確定你能不能撐到那兒
But luckily for you guys, there's another option
但幸運的是，你們還有另一個選擇
I have a boat named as $$ money
我有一條船，就叫它小金船吧
I can send this boat to you guys
我可以把這艘船送給你們
You can hop into that boat and can easily make it to this island
你可以上我的船，很容易就能到達這個島
But herein lies the problem
但這就是問題所在
A replica of your island is at this end of the sea
你們島嶼的複製品就在海的這一端
And I can send my boat in only one direction
而我隻能把我的船隻送往一個方嚮
But sir shouldn't we get the investment since its our original idea?
但是，先生，既然這是我們最初的想法，我們不應該得到投資嗎？
But guys..
但是……
Because I own the boat
因為這船是我的
Only I can make that choice
隻有我能做出這樣的選擇
And as unfortunate as it may sound
雖然聽起來很不幸
The ball right now is..
但是現在決定權
..completely in my court
完全在我的手上
I know its confidential, that's why I called you
我知道這是機密，所以我才打電話給你
Your promotion's on stake? I'll call you later then. Okay bye
你的晉升要出問題? 那我晚點給你打電話.好的，再見
Guys, thing is that Bhardwaj is not gonna disclose the names
夥計們，巴德瓦伊不會透露對方的名字
And Bangalore team is also uncommunicative
班加羅爾的團隊也不開口
Realistically its tough to get the names
實際上很難知道他們是誰
Puneet, can you work something out?
普尼特，你能想出辦法來嗎？
I'm trying but there's another problem
我正在努力，但還有一個問題
Bhardwaj is leaving for Dubai day after tomorrow
巴德瓦伊後天就要去迪拜了
What then?
然後呢？
I'll sort it out in a 2nd meeting tomorrow, Don't worry I have some contacts
我會在明天的第二次會議上解決這個問題，別擔心，我有一些關係
I'll call them and get back to you
我會打電話給他們，然後再打給你
Shit man
該死！
Are you sure that Puneet didn't leak our idea?
你確定普尼特冇有泄露我們的想法？
No no his own promotion is on stake, he didn't do it
不，不，他自己的晉升危在旦夕，不是他幹的
What's the matter Shreya? You know I have a meeting today
史瑞雅怎麼了? 你知道我今天要開會
Then why are you calling me over and over?
那你為什麼一遍又一遍地給我打電話？
I'm facing a huge problem here, I can't come right now
我遇到了一個大問題，我現在不能來
But at least tell me what's the matter?
但至少告訴我怎麼了？
Alright I'm coming, Yeah I'll be there
好的，我來了，好的，我馬上到
Guys I'll be back in 20, Call me if Puneet comes up with anything
夥計們，我20分鍾後回來，如果普尼特有什麼消息給我打電話
We should make a list of probable suspects
我們應該列一張嫌疑人的名單
Would that help?
那會有幫助嗎？
I have a lot of experience with larceny
我有很多反盜竊的經驗
When I was in MBA 1st year, someone used to steal my water bucket on alternate days
我讀 MBA 一年級的時候，有人隔天就會偷我的水桶
So I formed a list and applied base theorem, Turned out culprit was from my wing
所以我列了一個錶並應用了基本定理，結果發現罪魁禍首是我的捨友
I have a hunch its somebody we know
我有預感是我們認識的人
Mandal, where's your pen drive?
曼達爾，你的U盤呢？
I don't know, couldn't find it
我不知道，找不到了
I met Rastogi last weekend, since then its...
我上周末遇到了拉斯托吉，從那以後...
FUCK!
操！
Each and every demo and templates were in it
每個演示和模闆都在裏麵
Call that Rastogi now
現在就打給他
Call him you moron
快點，你個白癡
I'm sorry
對不起
Put it on speaker
開免提
He's in Bangalore, That's where he pitched our idea
他在班加羅爾，他就是在那裏偷走我們的想法的
Shit, do we have to go to Bangalore now?
媽的，我們現在一定要去班加羅爾嗎？
Wanna go to Bangalore motherfucker?
想去班加羅爾嗎？
Yeah Rastogi might be sitting in a coffee shop, jerking off to your name
是的，拉斯托吉可能正坐在咖啡店裏，對著你的名字打飛機
Please don't talk to me like that
請不要這樣跟我說話
I'll beat your ass you cunt face
我他媽打死你，你個傻逼
All you had to do Mandal was nothing Nothing
你要做的就是什麼都不做
That's all you had to do and you shit in that too
你的工作就是什麼都不做，然而你還是搞砸了
I've been telling Naveen since day 1 that we shouldn't include him
我從第一天開始就跟納文說我們不能把他算進去
I can tolerate his zero contribution But I can't put up with his negative contribution
我可以容忍他的零貢獻但我不能容忍他挖坑
We would've gotten the term sheet by now
本來我們現在應該拿到投資意嚮書了
Who gave you the right to fuck with our lives?
誰給你的權利來攪亂我們的計劃？
Yogi, why are you speaking like that, bro?
尤吉，你為什麼要這麼說，兄弟？
I'm already feeling guilty
我已經很內疚了
I didn't do it on purpose
我不是故意的
Yeah you can't do it on purpose, you know why?
是，你不是故意的，知道為什麼嗎？
Because you're a cunt
因為你是個混蛋
Yogi its enough Hold on a second
尤吉，夠了，別說了
You're a cunt The whole world knows that you're a cunt And you also know that you are a cunt
你是個賤貨，全世界都知道你是個賤貨，你自己也知道你是個賤貨
Stop talking to me like that Yogi
別這樣跟我說話，尤吉
Yes I know I made a mistake.
是的，我知道我犯了錯誤.
But we are friends...
但我們是朋友...
Really?
是嗎？
Then where are your other friends besides us?
那麼除了我們之外，你的其他朋友呢？
And why did you find Rastogi, of all people to drink beer with?
你為什麼偏偏找拉斯托吉一起喝酒？
Do you know why it was always your bucket that got stolen?
你知道為什麼總是你的水桶被偷嗎？
Because you're a pussy
因為你就是個賤貨
You're the biggest douchebag out there
你是個大傻逼
This ordeal that we are suffering is a punishment for involving cunts like you in our team
我們所遭受的這種摺磨是對你這種賤人加入我們隊伍的懲罰
Okay then
那好吧
You won't have to suffer because of me again
你不用再為我受苦了
It was great working with you guys
和你們合作很愉快
I quit
我不幹了
Mandal...
曼達爾...
Yogi you shouldn't have...
尤吉，你不應該...
- Mandal... - Get lost
- 曼達爾...-趕緊滾
Take a stand in your life just this once and don't ever come back you damn sore loser
做出明智的決定，永遠不要回來，你這該死的輸不起的家夥
What are you doing Yogi?
你都幹了些什麼，尤吉？
Shreya
史瑞亞
Hold on a minute Just a sec
等一下等一下
Aunty, can you move it?
阿姨，你能把它移開嗎？
Who are you calling aunty?
你叫誰阿姨呢？
Madam, can you please move it?
大姐，你能把它移開嗎？
Come on that side
我們去那邊
What is this nonsense? you've never been so unreasonable
你這是在鬨什麼，你從來冇有這麼不講道理過
I was in the middle of a meeting and you kept calling over & over
我正在開會，你一直打電話過來
Remember Rio? That job interview I had?
還記得裏約熱內盧嗎? 我參加的那個麵試？
Yeah, what about that? You rejected it.
怎麼了? 你不是已經拒絕了.
Yes but they have new vacancies in their London office
是的，但是他們的倫敦辦事處有新的空缺
And they want me there ASAP
他們希望我盡快趕過去
Infact, I have to get back to them by tonight, latest.
事實上，我必須在今晚之前去他們那報到
For how long?
要去多久？
I thought you were happy here?
我以為你在這裏很開心？
I am... Ofcourse I am, but...
我當然很開心，但是...
Naveen, its a dream job in a dream city
納文，這是一個夢幻城市的理想工作
Its like a once in a lifetime opportunity
這是一生中隻有一次的機會
Have you decided then?
你決定了嗎？
I don't know
我不知道
I can't believe I have to choose between...
我真不敢相信我要在...
My future and our future
我的未來和我們的未來之間做選擇
And I don't want to make that choice all by myself
我不想一個人做出這樣的選擇
What can I say now, its your decision
現在我能說什麼呢，這是你的決定
What would you have done if you were in my place?
如果你是我，你會怎麼做？
I think you should go
我想你應該去
Mandal's phone is switched off
曼達爾手機關機了
Why do you flip out so much Yogi?
你為什麼對他發那麼大火，尤吉？
He's not gonna go anywhere, he'll be home after a couple of beers
他哪兒也不會去，喝了幾杯啤酒就回家了
Yogi, He's Mandal Will you take responsibility if he did anything stupid?
尤吉，如果他做了什麼蠢事你負的起責任嗎？
There's your asshole
混蛋回來了
Must be Soumya, I told her to come here after the interview
一定是桑亞，我讓她麵試結束後來這裏
Listen, keep your trap shut, I don't want her to get in a stew
聽著，閉上你的臭嘴，我不想讓她被你嚇到
I got it
我通過了
Interview was amazing, they are gonna send me an offer letter and I'm gonna join by next week
麵試很順利，他們會給我發offer，下周入職
Congrats Soumya... Congrats
恭喜你桑亞... 恭喜
I'm sorry Yogi, I didn't see you
對不起，尤吉，我冇看見你
No no, you guys carry on I'll be inside
不，不，你們繼續，我去裏麵
No no, its allright Actually this is for you
不，不，冇關係的，這個給你
What's in it? sweets?
裏麵是什麼，糖果嗎？
No, these are visiting cards from Vista prints, they delievered it in the morning
不，這些是打印店寄來的名片，他們早上送來的
Actually he told me that the quality of previous cards was quite shoddy so...
實際上他告訴我以前的卡質量很差，所以...
How did the meeting go?
你們會議開得怎麼樣？
It was great, presentation went pretty well Demo was amazing so..
非常棒，演示相當不錯 -演示非常棒的，所以...
We pitched it well, he liked it
總之我們做得很好，他很喜歡
Yeah meeting was great
是的，聊得很愉快
Did you talk to Dad?
你和爸爸談過了嗎？
No
冇有
Actually I could talk to my Dad only He was asking about you and dad
其實隻有在我爸問到你和你爸的時候才能聊幾句
I have a hunch that dad knows about it
我有預感爸爸知道這件事
So, I think first I should talk to you and then dad
所以，我想我應該先和你談談，然後再和爸爸談
Why? you should talk to dad first
為什麼，你應該先和爸爸談談
How can you married couple can tell the difference between whose dad we're talking about
你們是怎麼分辨出說的是誰爸爸呢？
Okay, I'll talk to dad but should I say?
好吧，我會跟爸爸說的，但是我應該怎麼說？
Say what you always say
說你經常說的話
I know we disagree with him but we don't disrespect him. You should call him
我知道我們不同意他的意見，但我們不能不尊重他.你應該給他打電話
Puneet is calling
普尼特來電話了
Yeah, hi Puneet Its Yogi here
普尼特，我是尤吉
Yeah look Yogi, I couldn't find the name directly
餵，聽著，尤吉，我不能直接找到名字
But I have Bhardwaj's last week schedule right in front of me
但是我這有巴德瓦伊上周的日程安排
I have the details of all of his previous meetings
我有他以前所有會麵的詳細情況
Can you check if he had any meeting with Rastogi?
你能查一下他是否和拉斯托吉見過麵嗎？
Yeah, check for a Rastogi
查查有冇有叫拉斯托吉的
No no Rastogi with an R, yes
不，不，拉斯托吉有一個 r，是的
There's no Rastogi here Yogi
冇有拉斯托吉
No Rastogi?
冇有拉斯托吉？
Why don't you check alphabetically? and tell me the names starting from A
你按字母順序檢查一下? 從 a 開始挨個念一遍
There are almost 80 names here, I have already cross checked the list
這裏有將近80個名字，我已經交叉核對過了
Either they are big companies or already funded startups
他們要麼是大公司，要麼是已經註資的創業公司
There's only one slot left with no name but just an Email ID
隻剩下一個冇有名字的，隻有一個電子郵箱
What is the Email ID?
什麼是電子郵箱？
Some peculiar ID, yes...
某種特殊的身份，是的...
dungeon_master@hotmail.com there's an underscore between dungeon and master
地下城主@hotmail. com 地下城和主人之間有一個下劃線
FUCK!!!!!!!!!!
我操！！！
Oh fuck!
哦，操！
Why did you choose this place to talk about such an important matter
你為什麼選擇這個地方來談論這麼重要的事情
We could've gone to a restaurant
我們本可以去餐廳聊的
Maybe because I wanted to walk down the aisle with you once
也許是因為我想跟你走一次紅毯
Good to know, that your sense of humour is still intact
很好，你的幽默感還在
And good to see, that your "career comes first" ideology is still intact
你的“事業第一”思想仍然保持著我也很欣慰
Naveeeeeen!
納文！
Please say it
說出來吧
Just say it once that I love you, I can't live without you, please don't leave me
隻要說一次我愛你，冇有你我活不下去，請不要離開我
Shreya, I love you, I can't live without you
史瑞雅，我愛你，冇有你我活不下去
But please go
但是請你走吧
We'll try and figure out something
我們會想辦法的
Like what?
比如什麼？
Long distance?
異地戀？
You know that never works
你知道那是行不通的
I might never come back
我可能再也不會回來了
You can't move there and I can't be here
你不能搬到那裏，我也不能呆在這裏
Let's not try to take the easy way out, okay?
我們不要把問題簡單化，好嗎？
There's still time. I'll give you a coin, make the trial room your jury room
還有時間，我給你一枚硬幣，你去找個審判室做個決定
That is not gonna change anything
這改變不了什麼
I know you too well you know thats the problem
我太了解你了，這就是問題所在
You're getting very predictable you know
你知道嗎，你變得越來越可預測了
You're not instigating me, please stop trying
你說不動我的，別說了
Listen, really? You're letting me go? me?
聽著，真的嗎? ，你要放我走? ，我？
You're letting this and this and these and that go?
你要讓這個，這個，這個，還有那個走了？
Do you realize how tough it is to get this combination?
你知道得到這個組合有多難嗎？
It won't be tough, it will be impossible
不是難，而是不可能的
But its your job You have to do it
但這是你的工作，你必須要去
You know that your work is the only thing that will be here long after you're gone
你的工作是你死後唯一長久存在的東西
Naveen, that's just a figure of speech
納文，那隻是一種比喻
We're not Gandhi, Newton or Shakespeare
我們不是甘地，牛頓或者莎士比亞
Our work is just gonna get buried with our graves Its as simple as that
我們的工作隻是一起白頭到老，就這麼簡單
That is not true Shreya
不是的，史瑞雅
Hold on a minute
等一下
What is this?
這是什麼？
Your head
你的頭
What nonsense?
認真點
Go on tell me what's this?
告訴我這是什麼？
Its a bottle, what else?
這是一個瓶子，怎麼了？
Who built it?
誰造出來的？
How would I know?
我怎麼知道？
You know when man used to live in caves 1000 years ago...
你知道1000年前人類住在山洞裏的時候...
Are you kidding me? We are going that back, are we?
你在開玩笑嗎? ，我們要回到一仟年前，是嗎？
Yeah we are going that back Listen to me
是的，聽我說
He would find it arduous to draw water from the rivers
山洞裏的人覺得從河裏取水很費勁
Then someone made a water container made of leaves But it wasn't durable
有人就用樹葉做了一個裝水的容器，但不耐用
Then someone noticed that exposing wet soil to direct sunlight turns it into clay
然後有人註意到，把濕土暴露在陽光直射下會變成粘土
And then someone else made a pot from that very clay
所以有人用這種粘土做了一個罐子
But that wasn't durable either
但這也不是長久之計
Then someone invented plastic
後來有人發明了塑料
And then someone else thought plastic would make a durable container
有人就認為塑料可以做成耐用的容器
Then someone else designed its shape, another person made it transparent
然後有人設計了它的形狀，另一個人把它變成透明的
Someone discovered the caps, and someone designed the threads of the cap
有人設計了蓋子，有人設計了擰蓋子的線路
And someone made a whole factory to manufacture bottles
有人建造了一個製造瓶子的工廠
in which thousands of people work just to make these bottles
成仟上萬的人工作，就為了製造這些瓶子
Millions of people have been working for so many years, Shreya so that we can make use of these bottles
成仟上萬的人工作了這麼多年，史瑞雅，所以我們今天有瓶子可以用
Maybe we don't acknowledge it but...
也許我們不想承認，但是...
...there work is still here long after they're gone
一代又一代人的工作成果還保留在世上
And this is just a bottle, Shreya
這隻是一個瓶子，史瑞雅
look at your surroundings You're standing at a museum of human work history
看看你的周圍，你正站在人類工作曆史的博物館
Just look around
看看周圍
And what better place to prove your point, right?
還有什麼更好的地方能證明你的觀點呢？
Like always you're right Mr. Bansal
你總是對的，班薩爾先生
Will you miss me?
你會想我嗎？
On some lonely nights, maybe
也許在某些寂寞的夜晚
You?
你呢？
Every night
每天晚上都想
Pervert prick
死鬼
Well, I'll have to do something
好吧，我得做點什麼
Promise me that you'll give me a window of 3 months before you start seeing someone else
答應我，在你開始和別人約會之前，給我三個月的時間
Okay, and you also don't go on a selfie spree once you're in London
好吧，你也不要在倫敦瘋狂發自拍
Okay done
好的
We were sort of a soulmates type, right?
我們是靈魂伴侶，對吧？
We would be marrying for sure if I had been here
如果我在這裏，我們肯定會結婚
Thank god it didn't happen
感謝上帝，冇有讓這種事發生
So, technically we're breaking up
所以，嚴格來說，我們要分手了
We never got into technicalities baby
我們從來冇有涉及到技術細節，寶貝
No, I'm saying that because...
不，我這麼說是因為...
...it makes for a breakup sex for one last time
這是分手炮了
Ofcourse
當然
I'm leaving for home tonight for one week, We'll get to that once I'm back
我今晚要回家一個星期，等我回來再說
Anyway, I'll be leaving next week...
不管怎樣，我下周就要走了...
Okay, listen
好吧聽著
I think I should go now
我想我該走了
I have a flight to catch in the evening and I haven't even started packing yet
我晚上還要趕飛機，還冇開始收拾行李呢
Okay?
好嗎？
I'll talk to you tomorrow
我明天再打電話給你
Listen...
納文...
Here, keep this
拿著這個
- What's this? - 1767 (*PIN no.)
- 這是什麼?-密碼1767
Why are you giving me your credit card? what nonsense?
你為什麼給我你的信用卡? 別鬨？
Don't be a hero in front of me, I know your financial situation
不要在我麵前逞英雄，我知道你的經濟狀況
Groceries are on me for a month, okay?
食品雜貨我管你一個月，好嗎？
And its not a gift, I'm giving you a loan
這不是禮物，我是借給你的
You can pay me later
你可以以後再付我錢
Okay?
好嗎？
Naveen
納文
Naveen don't do this, not here, okay?
納文，別這樣，別在這兒好嗎？
You know I can't leave like this
你知道我不能就這樣離開
What happened?
怎麼了？
I had to do a lot of sacrifices for the startup
為了創業，我不得不做出很多犧牲
I gave up a decent job, decent salary, good stantard of living
我放棄了一份體麵的工作，體麵的薪水，良好的生活條件
And it never bothered me
這些都無所謂
But now you are sacrificing for my work
但是現在你為我的工作犧牲了
It hurts me a lot
這讓我很心疼
Hurts like hell
疼得要命
But if didn't hurt then its not gonna be a sacrifice, right?
但是如果不疼，那就不算犧牲了，不是嗎？
And there'll be a time when you're gonna be on the cover of TIME magazine
總有一天你會登上時代雜誌的封麵
then this'll all seem worth it
那這一切都值了
But just please make sure that happens, okay?
但是一定要確保這一點，好嗎？
For us, Okay?
為了我們，好嗎？
Bye, I'll call you
再見，我會打電話給你
Thats why I was getting a lot of Emails lately regarding Hair therapy
我說我最近怎麼收到很多生發廣告的電子郵件
He's been fucking with me since 6 months
他從6個月前就開始整我了
And you were gonna replace me with him?
你之前還打算用他來取代我？
Yeah because of financial crunch
是的，因為冇錢
Learn to apologize, Yogi
你要嘗試道歉，尤吉
Nah, apologies are stupid
不，道歉太蠢了
But I'm sure these assholes will be grovelling when I'll stamp their asses with my shoes
但我敢肯定，當我踩在他們屁股上的時候，這些混蛋會道歉的
Yogi please, you ought to be calm
尤吉，拜托，你冷靜一下
You're in a black mood since morning, let me handle this with patience
你從早上起就心情不好，讓我來處理吧
Okay but if they aggravated me, I'll fuck their shit up
好吧，但是如果他們激怒我，我他媽搞死他們
They are only 17 years old kids, I'll talk some sense into them
他們隻有17歲，我要勸勸他們
Allright, you talk and I'll kick Okay? lets go
好吧，你先說，說不通我在動手，好嗎? ，我們走
And they're lucky that I didn't put on my woodland shoes today
他們很幸運，我今天冇穿運動鞋
The fuck happened here?
這裏到底發生了什麼？
Where are those blockheads from last time?
上次那些笨蛋在哪裏？
What's that? Looks like someone took a shit here
- 那是什麼?-看起來是屎
Come on hurry up, lets do our business
來吧，快點，我們做正事
Come Yogi, come we were waiting for you
來了老弟，我們等你半天了
you guys knew we were coming?
你們知道我們要來嗎？
No no, we just like to sit like this everynight from 8 to 10
不，不，我們隻是喜歡每天晚上8點到10點這樣坐著
We got a hold of main gate's CCTV surveilance right here
我們這裏有大門的監控
Baby, you got your dramatic entry, Can I go now?
寶貝，你的華麗出場可以了，我能走了嗎？
Yeah okay
好吧
you're taking me to spa in the evening, right?
你晚上會帶我去泡溫泉，對嗎？
Banali, I'm working
班娜麗，我在工作
Look guys...
小夥子們...
You know why we are here
你知道我們為什麼來這裏
It took a lot of elbow grease for us to make that product
我們費了很大力氣才創造出那種産品
You guys did a mistake and its illegal too
你們犯了一個錯誤，這也是違法的
And you guys are just kids in college, we're not gonna lodge a complaint against you
你們隻是大學生，我們不會告你的
You made a mistake, its alright.
你隻是犯了個錯誤，冇關係.
You just need to call Bhardwaj and backout
你隻需要打電話給巴德瓦伊，跟他說退出
Relax, we're not taking any action against you
放鬆，我們不會對你採取任何行動
Jeetu, this guy is very cute
傑圖，這家夥很可愛
If you'll track the IP address, you'll get Mulund's cyber cafe
如果你追蹤這個 IP 地址，你會查到穆倫德的網吧
You ain't got shit on me
你冇有任何籌碼
Look, we have all the proofs which claims that this is our idea
聽著，我們有證據錶明這是我們的主意
I'm telling you for your own good, you guys are in college
我告訴你們是為了你們好，你們都上大學了
You'll get into trouble when your parents get to know about it
當你父母知道這件事的時候，你會有麻煩的
i'm not scared of my parents
我不怕我的父母
If our parents had enough time to reprove us...
如果我們的父母有足夠的時間來管我們...
...then you wouldn't be dealing with a brat like me
那你就不會和我這樣的小屁孩打交道了
Hold on a second, Jeetu Give me your phone
等一下，傑圖，把你的電話給我
Give me your phone and I'll tell these fucks who to call. Ambulance or Bhardwaj?
把你的電話給我，我會告訴這些混蛋該打給誰.救護車還是巴德瓦伊？
Give me your phone
把你手機給我
have you met Reddy?
你見過雷迪嗎？
Reddy was very fond of video chatting
雷迪非常喜歡視頻聊天
He cajoled a Bulgarian girl on omegle
他在陌陌上哄騙了一個保加利亞女孩
And then every night he used to skype with her, doing some nasty nasty...
然後每天晚上他都會和她視頻聊天做一些下流的事...
But little did he know that I was recording all the chats
但他不知道我錄下了所有的視頻
And one day...
有一天...
I uploaded all the video chats on the internet
我把所有的視頻聊天都上傳到了網上
It took him a lot of grovelling to do for me to take those videos down
我費了好大勁才把那些視頻撤下來
And this is my best friend we're talking about
這可是我最好的朋友
While you are a mutual friend of my father's third cousin
而你是我父親第三個堂兄的共同朋友
You gonna login at 1 AM tonight, right?
你會在今晚一點上線，對嗎？
Svetlana is a single mom
斯維特拉娜是個單身母親
And also an entrepreneur in many ways
在很多方麵也是一個企業家
41gb material, Reddy just got a new hard drive for it
41G的視頻，雷迪剛剛為它買了一個新的硬盤
It helped a lot during dry day, say her thanks for me
在這些欲火中燒的日子裏真的太感謝她了，幫我跟她說聲謝謝
Dare not touch, Yogi
別動哦，尤吉
Got a free router with my new computer
我的新電腦有免費的路由器
Wanna test the upload speed?
想試試上傳速度嗎？
Guys, please...
老哥們，拜托了
Bill stomped on Steve to create Microsoft
比爾坑了史蒂夫，創建了微軟
Then who are you?
所以你們是誰？
Go back the same way you came
滾吧
If you even tried to contact Bhardwaj...
如果你試圖聯係巴德瓦伊.
...then Yogi-Svetlana's folder won't only be in Reddy's hard drive
那麼尤吉和斯維特拉娜的文件夾就不僅僅在雷迪的硬盤裏了
Okay, lets go
好吧，我們走
Assholes
混蛋
Entrepreneurs?
企業家？
Telling me to backout
還想讓我退出
Hey Jeetu, come on I'm not convinced yet
嘿 傑圖，別走啊，我還冇被說服呢
Come and convince me that I should backout
來說服我，讓我退出
Convince me asshole
說服我啊，混蛋
What did you say?
你說什麼？
Convince me
說服我
Convince you?
說服你？
Out of the way
讓開
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
This motherfucker asked me to convince him
這個混蛋讓我說服他
First I convinced my wife, then my dad, then my family
首先我說服了我的妻子，然後是我的父親，然後是我的家人
Son of a bitch is just 17
這癟犢子才他媽17歲
Motherfucker, my i7-4790k edition
混蛋，我的i7-4790k
What are you? some gangsters?
你們是什麼人? ，流氓嗎？
We're not gangsters
我們不是流氓
We are entrepreneurs, motherfucker
我們是企業家
You know how much it costs to get your child into junior KG?
你知道讓孩子上幼兒園要花多少錢嗎？
Do you have any idea about house mortgaging?
你們了解過房屋抵押嗎？
I went to the grocery store yesterday
我昨天去了雜貨店
You know how much does baby corn cost?
你知道小玉米要多少錢嗎？
Rs 120 per 100 grams
每100克120盧比
Oh my, Rs 1200 per kg? Damn!
哦，天哪，每公斤1200盧比? 該死！
What did I want?
我的需求是什麼？
That you get your seed fund and I get my promotion, Is that too much to ask for?
你拿到你的種子基金，我升職，這要求過分嗎？
You hardly faced a challenge and 25% percent of the team has resigned already
幾乎冇有任何難度，而且1/4的團隊成員已經辭職了
Puneet, he has switched off his phone, how is that our fault?
普尼特，他手機關機了，跟我們有什麼關係
Naveen, talk some sense itno him dude
納文，跟他講講道理
I'm tired of talking now, you should do it
我已經不想說話了，你講吧
Is this the team that I've advocated for?
這就是我要支持的團隊嗎？
This CEO attends meeting without even taking a shower or freshen up
這位首席執行官參加會議時甚至冇有洗澡或梳洗一番
This CEO curses and bullies people
這位首席運營官滿嘴髒話還欺負人
This CTO vandalizes the computers
這個首席技術官瘋狂砸電腦
This seems like a million dollar team, howcome no one has decided to fund you yet?
看起來是一個百萬美元的團隊，為什麼還冇有人投你們呢？
Puneet, he's coming
普尼特，他來了
Alright let bygones be bygones, just don't say anything to Bhardwaj
好吧，過去的就讓它過去吧，隻是不要告訴巴德瓦伊
I'll do the talking, okay?
我來說，好嗎？
Okay lets go
好了，我們走
Are you alright? you seem gloomy
你還好嗎? ，你看起來很沮喪
Hi guys, sorry I got stuck on a call
嗨，對不起，我被電話拖住了
How're you guys doing?
你們怎麼樣？
Good, sir
很好，先生
Where is uhh...
曼達爾在哪裏...
Uhh Manda...uhh Saurabh is unwell actually so he won't be joining us today
曼達爾身體不適，所以他今天不能參加了
Okay, no problem
好的，冇問題
Ankit, I was talking to Naveen and these guys really want to renegotiate the terms
安基特，我和納文談過了，他們真的想重新談談條件
Puneet, can you sit this one out?
普尼特，你能不參加這次會議嗎？
I'm really sorry but I want to talk to the guys directly
我真的很抱歉，但我想直接和他們談談
So, if you can take a break, it'd be great
所以，如果你能休息一下，那就太好了
I know this means a lot to you, you've worked very hard on your product
我知道這對你來說意義重大，你為你的産品付出了很多
And, I really appreciate the amount of hard work that you've put in
而且，我真的很感激你們所做的努力
But...
但是...
Last night I had a chat with the other team And...
昨晚我和另一隊聊了一下然後...
They are offering me a much better deal now
他們現在給了我一個更好的條件
From here on I can virtually own that company
從現在開始我就可以直接擁有那家公司了
So... I have no reason why I shouldn't invest in them
所以... 我冇有理由不投資他們
But don't you think sir its.. what they have done is illegal?
但是你不認為他們的所作所為是違法的嗎？
Like we've got our product registered and there are copywrite laws...
就像我們的産品已經註冊了專利，應該受到專利法保護……
You can copywrite a product but you can't copywrite an idea
你可以複製一個産品，但你不能複製一個想法
Selling goods online is an idea
在網上銷售商品是一個想法
But Flipkart, Snapdeal, Amazon they are all selling it
但是 Flipkart，Snapdeal，亞馬遜，他們都用
I think sir its extremely unfair to us
先生，我認為，這對我們非常不公平
-Like we've been working on this for... -Look guys...
- 我們做出的努力...-聽著夥計們...
As a human being, I genuinely feel sorry for you
作為一個人，我真的為你感到難過
But as an investor, I can't let that feeling come in my way
但作為一個投資者，我不能讓這種感覺阻礙我
And if I want to do a business then I ought to look out for my self interest, right?
如果我想做生意，那麼我應該為自己的利益著想，對嗎？
Sir like, Puneet knew about it since the beginning
普尼特從一開始就知道這件事
May I come in, sir?
我能進來嗎，先生？
Saurabh?
曼達爾？
I thought you were sick
我以為你病了
Too bad you came all the way because...
很抱歉你大老遠跑來...
I have nothing but bad news for you
我隻有壞消息要告訴你
Its okay sir, but can I give you a presentation?
冇關係，先生，我可以給您做個演示嗎？
Presentation? I just told them that I've made up my mind and there's no point in...
演示? 我隻是告訴他們我已經下定決心了，冇有必要...
Please sir
求你了，先生
I spent Rs 35000 to make this presentation
我花了35000盧比買回來的
I know you have seen all the company documents but sir this will make our company really big
我知道你已經看過了所有的公司文件，但是先生，這個演示將使我們公司上一個臺階
I'll need just 2 minutes sir
我隻需要兩分鍾，先生
Alright, go ahead
好吧，開始吧
Naveen's Team by Saurabh Mandal
【納文的團隊】作者: 曼達爾
This team consists of 4 members
這個團隊由4名成員組成
Naveen Bansal
納文·班薩爾
Jitendra Maheshwari
傑圖德拉·馬赫什瓦裏
Yogendra Kumar Pandey
尤吉德拉 · 庫馬爾 · 潘迪
And me, Saurabh Mandal
還有我，索拉佈 · 曼達爾
Let's begin with Jeetu
讓我們從傑圖開始
All of us have a Mr Sharma's son(*Stereotypical intellectual son) in our life
我們每個人的生活中都有一個知識分子的兒子
But in Bikaner's Government high school, there was a Mr Maheshwari's son
但是在比卡內爾的政府高中，有一位馬赫什瓦裏先生的兒子
Jitendra Maheshwari
傑圖德拉·馬赫什瓦裏
Sir, I've never seen a live performance of Backstreet Boys
先生，我從來冇有看過後街男孩的現場錶演
But I've seen Jeetu writing code
但是我看到過傑圖寫代碼
Continuously for 36 hours, without any sleep
連續36小時不睡覺
He could've easily gone to US to work for facebook
他本可以去美國為 facebook 工作
But he didn't leave India for his family's sake
但他為了家庭冇有離開印度
Afterall he is a family man
畢竟他是個顧家的人
And now for the first time in his life he went against his family for this startup
現在，這是他有生以來第一次為了這家創業公司與家人作對
Why? Why did he do it?
為什麼? 他為什麼這麼做？
Yogi
尤吉
Sir, some people know very few people
先生，有些人認識的人很少
Some people know most of the people
有些人認識的人很多
But Yogi knows everyone
但是尤吉認識所有人
Naveen told me that when they visited Gujarat(*Dry state) Yogi arranged for a beer at 4 in the morning
納文告訴我，當他們訪問古吉拉特時，尤吉安排在淩晨4點喝啤酒
I learned more about Cost cutting from Yogi than from my MBA lectures
我從尤吉那裏學到了很多關於削減成本的知識，而不是在MBA課程學來的
He bought a cake of just Rs. 25 for his birthday
他買了一塊二十五裏拉的蛋糕作為生日禮物
He had a CGPA of just 5.3(out of 10)
他的平均 gpa 隻有5.3(滿分10分)
But he got a salary package of Rs 2.2 million
但是他年薪220萬盧比
He would've been the Mumbai regional head in just 2 years had he been working there
如果他在那裏工作的話，兩年內他就會成為孟買的地區負責人
But then why did he leave his job for this startup? Why is he fighting tooth and nail for this startup?
但是他為什麼要離開他的工作去創業呢？ 為什麼他要竭盡全力這個創業公司奮鬥？
Only to let his hair fall?
難道是為了加快脫發？
Why?
為什麼？
And finally
最後
Naveen Bansal
納文·班薩爾
I love watching movies
我喜歡看電影
In the end of every movie, there's director's name written under "A film by"
每部電影的結尾都有"由xx指導"的一行字
I used to get angry by seeing that
我過去常常因為看到這個而生氣
I mean...
我是說...
Actor acts, writer writes and cinematographer shoots the film
演員錶演，編劇寫劇本，攝影師拍攝
Then what does the director do that he gets such a special attention
那麼導演做了什麼使他得到如此特別的關註呢
All he has to do is to make a choice Good or bad
他所要做的就是做選擇，好還是壞
But Naveen has realised me that choices are the most challenging things in life
但是納文意識到，選擇是生活中最具挑戰性的事情
Sir, this whole idea is Naveen's
先生，這整件事都是納文的主意
This is his product
這是他的産品
This is his team
這是他的團隊
If there's anyone in this world for whom we all can take a bullet
我們都可以為他擋子彈
This is the gentleman sitting over here
這就是坐在這裏的那位先生
For this team, he made our home office and his own home was turned itno a warehouse
為了這個團隊，他把我們的家庭辦公室和他自己的家變成了一個倉庫
This is the man who didn't like to iron his own shirts, who now volunteers to launder all of our clothes
這就是那個不喜歡自己熨襯衫的人，他現在自願幫我們洗所有的衣服
All of us have done a lot of sacrifices for each other
我們所有人都為彼此做出了很多犧牲
But Naveen has done a lot more than that to shield us
但是納文為了保護我們所做的遠不止這些
Why is Naveen doing all this?
為什麼納文要這麼做？
All of us
我們為什麼要這麼做？
Why all of us are so hell-bent for this startup?
為什麼我們所有人都對這家創業公司如此執著？
I'll tell you why sir
我來告訴你為什麼，先生
Because we all want to reach here
因為我們都想到達這裏
And we're not waiting for any boat
我們不會等任何船
We're already swimming in the sea of unknown
我們已經在未知的海洋中漂流
We've already left our comfort zone long ago
我們早就離開了我們的舒適區
Now we don't care about the changes, challenges or sacrifices we'll have to face
現在我們不關心我們將要麵對的變化、挑戰或犧牲
No matter what
無論如何
Our team will reach here, where magic happens
我們的隊伍會到達這裏，奇跡發生的地方
And what do you do in your team?
你在你的團隊裏是做什麼的？
Sir, I don't have any value individually
先生，我個人冇有任何價值
I'm a zero
我是空氣
But the net value increases by 10 times when I add up
但是我的加入使公司淨值增加了10倍
You've made your point
你已經說得很清楚了
Now let me make my point very clear
現在讓我把我的觀點再強調一下
No matter which team gets here
不管哪支隊伍來到這裏
It's ultimately going to be me who's going to shape their idea and make them a bigger company
最終我將塑造他們的想法，讓他們成為一個更大的公司
You need business business expertise to build this things
這需要業務專業知識來構建這些東西
And, at the risk of sounding arrogant let me tell you guys that
聽起來可能很傲慢，但讓我告訴你們
The team which I shall support, that team would be the strongest
我選擇的團隊一定是最強的
And that team will make a bigger company
這個團隊必將成為一個更大的公司
And I think you guys are forgetting that, I've already decided to back the other team
我想你們忘了，我已經決定投資另一隊了
Sir, you're also forgetting something
先生，你還忘了一件事
Yours is not the only island in the sea
你的島不是海裏唯一的島嶼
There are other magical islands
還有其他神奇的島嶼
Who'll be more than happy to have us on the shore
他們也很願意拉我們上岸
So you're saying that...
所以你是說...
You've offers from other investors as well?
還有其他投資者有投資意嚮？
Sir, do you really think that we presented our product to just one investor?
先生，你真的認為我們隻嚮一個投資者展示産品嗎？
And who are these investors exactly?
這些投資者到底是誰？
Sorry sir, I can't reveal their names at this point of time
對不起，先生，我現在不能透露他們的名字
You know my reputation guys
你們知道我的名聲
If I reject your idea, then no one will dare to invest here with you
如果我拒絕你的想法，那麼冇有人敢在這裏給你們投資
And sir you know our perseverance
先生，你知道我們的毅力
We'll surely make it up to there
我們一定會上岸的
Either in your portfolio or in your anti-portfolio
無論是在你的投資組合中還是在你的反投資組合中
I play poker a lot
我經常玩撲克
I know a bluff when I see one
我一看就知道你是在虛張聲勢
You have no other offers
你冇有別的選擇
You're trying to play on my fear of losing out
你在利用我害怕失敗的心理
When the fact is...
事實就是...
Apart from me
除了我
You've nowhere else to go
你無處可去
Sir, the ball is still in your court
好吧，被你識破了
Stay here Mandal, where are you going?
呆在這兒，曼達爾，你要去哪兒？
No, I'm going home
不，我要回家
I have to draft a formal resignation letter
我得起草一份正式的辭職信
Whatever happened to your "perseverance" and "making up to the island"?
你的“毅力”和“上岸”哪去了？
Now that we're telling you to stay, you're walking out
我們要你留下你還非要走
No, too much emotional attachment is bad
不，過多的情感依戀是不好的
Whatever happened, happened for the best
無論發生了什麼，都是最好的結果
Sit-down asshole
坐下，混蛋
Didn't you hear me asshole? come back
你冇聽見我說話嗎，混蛋，回來
Why do you want me to stay if I'm an asshole?
如果我是個混蛋，你為什麼還要我留下？
Because you're my friend motherfucker
因為你是我的朋友，混蛋
Come on now, sit-down here
過來，坐下
I won't
我不會的
It was just a presentation, don't try to be a hero now
那隻是一個演示，現在不要想逞英雄
I was in a black mood yesterday, come on back here
我昨天心情不好，回來吧
I said I won't
我說了我不會
I know I overreacted yesterday, try to understand what I'm saying
我知道我昨天反應過度了，試著理解我在說什麼
understand what?
理解什麼？
That I'm saying sorry motherfucker
我說對不起，混蛋
Now come back here or I'll whoop your ass
現在給我回來，不然我揍你
It's okay I forgive you
冇關係，我原諒你
We got it
我們拿到了
We go it Jeetu
我們成功了，傑圖
Guys put me down
我要倒了
I told you what my pen drive could do
我告訴過你我的U盤能做什麼
Cheers
幹杯
Let's take about 10 such pitchers to home, we'll get some fine quality beer with a lot of froth
哥幾個，今晚不醉不歸
We've only got 10% of the seed fund, don't fuck this up before paperwork
我們隻有10% 的種子基金，別在文書工作之前搞砸了
Says the guy who recently fucked it up in a hostel
這話出自一個最近在青年旅社砸電腦的家夥之口
It was exhilerating though, wasn't it?
不過還是很開心的，不是嗎？
Half of my frustration was because you broke my phone
我很生氣有一半是因為你砸了我的手機
Give me your phone, I need to talk to Soumya
把你的手機給我，我要和桑亞說一聲
Naveen, I think our new office should be in the vicinity of Powai lake
納文，我覺得我們的新辦公室應該在寶威附近
The research says that if you see water every morning, your blood cells are tend to increase by 12%
研究錶明，如果你每天早上看到水，你的血細胞會增加12%
We can hardly afford 1 BHK there fucker
我們付不起那的房租，混蛋
We need someone for UYOS, Jeetu needs a developer, we need an office setup, I need an intern
我們需要網絡運維，傑圖需要程序員，我們需要一個辦公室室，我需要一個實習生
Don't worry, our CEO Mr. Bansal will give us everything. We'll get everything
別擔心，我們的首席執行官班薩爾先生會給我們一切
No one ever gets everything dude
冇有人能得到一切，兄弟
There are some things which are never meant to be yours
有些東西註定不屬於你
What the hell happened to you?
你最近到底怎麼了？
No nothing, I'm just kidding
冇什麼，我開玩笑的
Okay you guys enjoy, I need to make a phone call
好了，你們慢用，我要打個電話
Naveen? hi
納文，你好
Hey Rathore, how are you bro?
嘿 拉索爾，你好嗎？
I'm doing great, what about you?
我很好，你呢？
You were in final year, what are you doing here?
你現在是大四吧，你在這裏做什麼？
No no, I graduated last year I have a job here now
不，不，我去年畢業的，我現在在這裏工作
That's great. you've grown up
太好了，你長大了
No dude, you're the one who's doing great
不，夥計，你才是那個成功人士
I just liked your facebook status
我有關註你的Facebook狀態
Oh, so you know about it?
哦，那麼你知道了？
Congratulations man, you aced it
恭喜你，老哥，你成功了
I'm feeling very jealous from you right now
我現在非常嫉妒你
Your life is gonna be awesome dude
你的未來一定會很精彩
While we will only get to fill excel sheets in our office
而我們隻能在辦公室填寫 excel 錶格
I've only got weekends to enjoy
隻有周末可以放鬆一下
Although I also thought about opening a startup but I couldn't give it enough time
雖然我也想過開一家創業公司，但我冇有足夠的時間
And even if I got enough time, nobody's luck is as good as yours
即使我有足夠的時間，也冇有你的運氣
Tell me one thing...
回答我一個問題
What are you?
你是什麼？